Guide to the Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions Records, Addendum
Yale University Divinity School Library
Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions Records - Addendum A
1886-1964
RG 42a
Yale University Divinity School Library
27
(63 boxes)
These records primarily document the last decade of the SVM's autonomous existence, 1949-1959, complementing the records found in Record Group No. 42. The Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions was an organization that sought to recruit college and university students in the United States for missionary service. In 1959, the Student Volunteer Movement, the United Student Christian Council, and the Interseminary Committee merged to form the National Student Christian Federation.
Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers
Biographical / Historical
The Student Volunteer Movement was established in 1886. It became the Commission on World Mission
of the merger-produced National Student Christian Federation of North America in 1959. See the finding aid for the Archives of the Student Volunteer Movement (Record Group No. 42) for more background information.
Scope and Contents
I. Volunteer and Inquirer Forms and Statistics
III. General Correspondence
IV. Financial Correspondence and Records
V. Organization and Policy Records
VI. Field Work
VII. Publications and Literature Distribution
VIII. Conventions
IX. Relationships with Other Organizations
X. Photographs
This record group should be used in conjunction with Record Group No. 42. The addendum primarily contains records from the time period 1948 to 1959, documenting the administrations of Edward H. Johnson (1948-1954) and L. Newton Thurber (1954-1958).
Arrangement
I. Volunteer and Inquirer Forms and Statistics
III. General Correspondence
IV. Financial Correspondence and Records
V. Organization and Policy Records
VI. Field Work
VII. Publications and Literature Distribution
VIII. Conventions
IX. Relationships with Other Organizations
X. Photographs
College students in missionary work; College students -- Religious life; Missions; Universities and colleges -- Religion; National Student Christian Federation; Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions
- Volunteer and Inquirer Forms and Statistics Addendum, Series I
  - Declaration Card revisions (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General Correspondence Addendum, Series III
  - Correspondence of SVM General Secretary R.H. Edwin Espy (1940-1943)
    - Beaven, Albert W., 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 187)
    - Bilheimer, Robert, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 188)
    - Bonsal, C.D., 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 189)
    - Bonsal, E.H., 1940-1943 (Box 26, Folder 190)
    - Braisted, Paul J., 1937-1952 (Box 26, Folder 191)
    - Byers, Elizabeth M., 1941-1950 (Box 26, Folder 192)
    - Campbell, F.E., 1939-1950 (Box 26, Folder 193)
    - Cole, George D., Jr., 1940-1945 (Box 26, Folder 194)
    - China/India Colleges: Requests for teachers/staff, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 195)
    - Earhart Foundation, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 196)
    - Edmands, Grant Mrs., 1939-1942 (Box 26, Folder 197)
    - Ehrensperger, Harold, 1941-1948 (Box 26, Folder 198)
    - Elliot, A.J., 1941-1943 (Box 26, Folder 199)
    - Elliot, A. Roland, 1939-1953 (Box 26, Folder 200)
    - Erdman, Mabel, 1941-1947 (Box 26, Folder 201)
    - Goetsch, F.A., 1940-1947 (Box 27, Folder 202)
    - Goodsell, Dr. F.F., 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 203)
    - Gould, Ivan M., 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 204)
    - Gray, James A., 1940-1950 (Box 27, Folder 205)
    - Groenfeldt, John S., 1941-1945 (Box 27, Folder 206)
    - Harbison, R., 1941-1945 (Box 27, Folder 207)
    - Hayes, E.M., 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 208)
    - Hill, W. Bancroft, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 209)
    - Hopkins, Mrs. John, 1940-1951 (Box 27, Folder 210)
    - Huggins, G.E., 1941-1955 (Box 27, Folder 211)
    - Julius, E.F., 1939-1946 (Box 27, Folder 212)
    - Koo, T.Z., 1930-1941 (Box 27, Folder 213)
    - Mackay, John A., 1939-1947 (Box 27, Folder 214)
    - Macmillan, Hugh, 1940-1947 (Box 27, Folder 215)
    - McGregor, Lawrence, 1939-1953 (Box 27, Folder 216)
    - Ross, Emory, 1940-1945 (Box 27, Folder 217)
    - Sharp, Tom, 1941-1952 (Box 27, Folder 218)
    - Taylor, H. Kerr, 1941-1954 (Box 27, Folder 219)
    - Tucker, Luther, 1939-1955 (Box 27, Folder 220)
  - Correspondence of SVM General Secretary Winburn Thomas (1943-1948)
    - Benson, Hilda, 1942-1947 (Box 27, Folder 221)
    - Blizzard, Samuel W., Jr., 1945 (Box 27, Folder 222)
    - Bollinger, Hiel D., 1944-1950 (Box 28, Folder 223)
    - Clausen, Christian F.W., 1943-1946 (Box 28, Folder 224)
    - Cory, Robert, 1943-1948 (Box 28, Folder 225)
    - Cowles, Benjamin, 1944-1950 (Box 28, Folder 226)
    - Dotzauer, Dorothy, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 227)
    - Downie, Gerald, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 228)
    - General Inquiries, 1944-1947 (Box 28, Folder 229)
    - Heylman, Mary Tooker, 1946-1951 (Box 28, Folder 230)
    - Holmstrom, Arvida, 1944-1956 (Box 28, Folder 231)
    - Markley, Mary, 1943-1950 (Box 28, Folder 232)
    - Miscellaneous correspondents, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 233)
    - Miscellaneous memos and notes, 1944 (Box 28, Folder 234)
    - Morris, Raymond, 1943-1953 (Box 28, Folder 235)
    - Mott, John R., 1943-1954 (Box 28, Folder 236)
    - Ralla Ram, Augustine, 1946-1946 (Box 28, Folder 237)
    - Raven, Canon, 1943-1954 (Box 28, Folder 238)
    - Reid, Ann T., 1944-1950 (Box 28, Folder 239)
    - Reisner, Sherwood H., 1943-1950 (Box 28, Folder 240)
    - Russell, Paul, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 241)
    - Seabury, Ruth, 1943-1954 (Box 28, Folder 242)
    - SVM of South Africa, 1945-1946 (Box 28, Folder 243)
    - Thompson, Sinclair, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 244)
    - Woodman, Eleanor, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 245)
  - Correspondence of SVM General Secretary E.H. Johnson (1948-1954)
    - Albright-Aulbach (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Babcock-Burgess (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Beck, Mary Alice, 1948-1951 (Box 28, Folder 246)
    - Cameron-Cuthbertson (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Campbell, E. Fay (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - David-Dunlop (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Eberhardt-Ewing (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Epstein
    - Faraday-Fulton (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Farrell, Nancy, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 248)
    - Gamble-Gunther (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Gamble, Sarah, 1948-1950 (Box 29, Folder 249)
    - Hall-Hutchinson (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ice-Isbister (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ingalls, Roscoe, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 250)
    - Jackson-Jung (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Jones, Tracey K., 1952 (Box 29, Folder 247)
    - Kaltenback-Kurtz (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Lacy-Luchring (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Liao, Chang, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 252)
    - Mahy-Munro (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Macmillan, Hugh (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Mackay, Dr. John (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - McConnel, J.J. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1954 (Box 29, Folder 251)
    - Miscellaneous re. missionary activity, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 254)
    - Mott, John R. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Nash-Neyman (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Ohio State University-Owen (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Palmore-Pratt (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Porter, David (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Ranck-Russel (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Rogers, Mrs. Walter A., 1948-1953 (Box 29, Folder 255)
    - Rossman, Parker (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Roy, Andrew Todd (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Samburg-Summers (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Sarah Marquis Travel Agency, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 253)
    - Shedd, Clarence (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Skalak, Anna, 1951-1953 (Box 29, Folder 256)
    - Tanaka-Unemoto (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Thomas, Winburn (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Van Doren-Vey (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Van Dusen, Henry Pitt (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Varker, Mary (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Vass, Lachlan (Mrs.) (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Viehman, Harold (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Watanabe-Wysner (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Wick, Ruth (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Williams, M.O. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Wilson, Carl W., 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 257)
    - Yandell-Yocum (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Young, Henry (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Zacharia-Zwemer (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence of other SVM Administrators
    - Anna L. Allison (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Mary Alice Beck (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Paul Converse (Athens Quadrennial) (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Paul Converse (General Correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
    - William Keys (Box 4, Folder 47-48)
    - William Keys (Box 29, Folder 258)
    - Miscellaneous, 5 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Financial Correspondence and Records Addendum, Series IV
  - Account book, 1937 (Box 29, Folder 259)
  - Account book, 1948-1952 (Box 29, Folder 260)
  - Account book, 1951-1953 (Box 30, Folder 260a)
  - Annual board contributions, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 261)
  - Appeals, 1939-1954 (Box 30, Folder 262)
  - Balance sheets, 1943-1944 (Box 30, Folder 263)
  - Budget and Finance Committee Documents (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
  - Budget and Finance Committee re. NCCCUSA and SVM merger, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 264)
  - Budget comparisons, 1950-1953 (Box 30, Folder 265)
  - Contributions, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 266)
  - Contributions -- Follow up, 1941-1950 (Box 30, Folder 267)
  - Contributions -- Foreign, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 268)
  - Contributors, 1940-1946 (Box 30, Folder 269)
  - Contributors -- Addresses, 1937-1943 (Box 30, Folder 270)
  - Contributors -- Addresses, 1943-1946 (Box 31, Folder 271)
  - Contributors -- Thank yous, 1940-1946 (Box 31, Folder 272)
  - Contributors -- Thank yous, 1945-1954 (Box 31, Folder 273)
  - Corn Exchange Bank Trust deposits, 1945-1951 (Box 31, Folder 274)
  - Donor receipt, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 275)
  - Duplicate deposit slips, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 276)
  - Duplicate deposit slips, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 277)
  - Employee exemption certificates, 1949-1953 (Box 31, Folder 278)
  - Expense calculations, 1942-1943 (Box 31, Folder 279)
  - Finance reports, 1939-1942 (Box 31, Folder 280)
  - Financial statements, 1939-1940 (Box 31, Folder 282)
  - Florence M. Collins' Will, 1940 (Box 31, Folder 283)
  - General budget, record of expenses, 1948, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 284)
  - General budget, 1948-1949 (Box 32, Folder 285)
  - General budget, 1948-1949 (Box 32, Folder 286)
  - General budget, 1949-1952 (Box 32, Folder 287)
  - General budget, 1951-1952 (Box 32, Folder 288)
  - General budget, 1954-1957 (Box 32, Folder 289)
  - Government deposit slips and information for withholding taxes, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 290)
  - Greenwich Savings Bank, 1944-1953 (Box 33, Folder 291)
  - Income and expenditures, financial estimates, 1946-1948, 1950-1951 (Box 33, Folder 292)
  - Invoices for purchases, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 293)
  - Long distance calls, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 294)
  - Main accounting system, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 295)
  - Member directory, 1941-1950 (Box 33, Folder 296)
  - Memo re. organizations not contributing to quadrennial conference, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 297)
  - Memos re. petty cash fund, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 298)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Receipts (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Notice of rent payments, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 299)
  - Proposed budget, 1941-1942 (Box 33, Folder 300)
  - Proposed budget, balance sheets, 1943-1944 (Box 33, Folder 301)
  - Receipts for bills paid, cash receipts, 1943-1944 (Box 33, Folder 302)
  - Receipts, 1951-1952 (Box 33, Folder 303)
  - Receipts and vouchers, 1951-1953 (Box 33, Folder 304)
  - Record of hours worked, 1951-1952 (Box 34, Folder 305)
  - Regional staff wages, 1951-1953 (Box 34, Folder 306)
  - Requests for cheques, 1951-1952 (Box 34, Folder 307)
  - Salaries of regional secretaries, 1950 (Box 34, Folder 308)
  - Salary and tax papers, 1949-1957 (Box 34, Folder 309)
  - Salary and tax papers, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 310)
  - Savings, Pension, and Insurance (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Sixtieth anniversary fund drive, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 311)
  - Special appeal on deficit, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 312)
  - SVM grants -- Home missions council of North America, 1949-1952 (Box 34, Folder 313)
  - SVM Grants -- Joint Commission on Missionary Education, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 314)
  - SVM Grants -- Intercollegian, 1948-1951 (Box 34, Folder 315)
  - SVM Grants -- SCM in New England, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 316)
  - SVM Grants -- USCC and WSCF, 1951-1954 (Box 34, Folder 317)
  - Tax information, 1944-1948 (Box 34, Folder 318)
  - Tax papers, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 319)
  - Telephone call records, 1949-1950 (Box 34, Folder 320)
  - Thank you note to Church of Canada, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 321)
  - Total scholarship grants and commitments, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 322)
  - Trial balance, 1938 (Box 34, Folder 323)
  - Trial balance, 1944-1948 (Box 34, Folder 324)
  - Trial balances, monthly billing figures, 1955-? (Box 35, Folder 325)
  - Various travel expenses, 1944-1948 (Box 35, Folder 326)
  - Vouchers -- Eleanor Ruhe, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 327)
  - Yale List: Correspondence with colleges, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 331)
  - Withholding income tax from wages information sheet, 1945 (Box 35, Folder 328)
  - Withholding tax statements, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 329)
  - Yale List: Acknowledgments of gifts, 1951-1952 (Box 35, Folder 330)
  - Yale List: General appeal letter, 1951-1952 (Box 35, Folder 332)
  - Yale List: Instructions, list, form letters, and unfinished work (Box 35, Folder 333)
  - Yale List: Letter to Board of Directors re. names of SVM volunteers who joined in 1914, 1920, 1924, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 334)
  - Yale List: 1951 group, obtaining new addresses (Box 35, Folder 335)
- Organization and Policy Records Addendum, Series V
  - Ad hoc Committee on Ecumenical Missions, 1956-1957 (Box 35, Folder 336)
  - Advisory Council minutes and correspondence re. participation of Interseminary Movement, 1941-1949 (Box 35, Folder 337)
  - Administrative Secretary Search 1952 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Annual Reports (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Annual report of General Secretary, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 338)
  - Board of Directors (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Board of Directors, 1944-1945, 1949 (Box 36, Folder 339)
  - Board of Directors Minutes, Memos, and Reports, 1948-1949 (Box 36, Folder 340)
  - Board of Directors Minutes and Memos, 1949-1950 (Box 36, Folder 341)
  - Board of Directors Minutes and Memos, 1950 (Box 36, Folder 342)
  - Board of Directors Minutes, Memos, and Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 36, Folder 343)
  - Board of Directors Minutes and Memos, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 344)
  - Board of Directors Minutes and Memos, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 345)
  - Board of Directors, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 346)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1936-1937 (Box 36, Folder 347)
  - By laws, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 348)
  - Campus Groups (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Candidate Secretaries (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Committee on Cycle of National Conferences (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Committee on Missionary Personnel (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Committee on Reconstruction and Pioneer Work, 1942-1944 (Box 37, Folder 349)
  - Conference on Mission of the Church, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 350)
  - Currie survey, 1940 (Box 37, Folder 351)
  - E.H. Johnson's Asia trip report, 1953 (Box 37, Folder 352)
  - E.H. Johnson's Expense Accounts (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - E.H. Johnson's Itinerary (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - E.H. Johnson's Questionnaire on World Mission (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - E.H. Johnson's Reports, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 353)
  - E.H. Johnson's Reports re. Traveling in the East, 1952-1953 (Box 37, Folder 354)
  - E.H. Johnson's Travel Expenses (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Executive Committee Documents (Box 7, Folder 64-65)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1946-1951 (Box 37, Folder 355)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1952-1953 (Box 37, Folder 356)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1953-1956 (Box 37, Folder 357)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 37, Folder 358)
  - Executive Committee Miscellaneous, 1956-1959 (Box 37, Folder 359)
  - General Secretary Search 1954 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Kirkridge Retreat Material (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Literature Committee (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Michigan SVM (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Miscellaneous Documents (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Miscellaneous Memos and Reports, 1943-1949 (Box 38, Folder 360)
  - Miscellaneous Memos and Reports, 1946-1948 (Box 38, Folder 361)
  - Miscellaneous Minutes and Notes, 1947 (Box 37, Folder 362)
  - Mission Statements (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Nominating Committee of SVM (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Nominating Committee Minutes, 1954-1955 (Box 38, Folder 363)
  - Office Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Ohio SVM (Frances Charrier, Oberlin) (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Personnel Committee (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Pledges: January 1948 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Pledges: February 1948 (Box 8, Folder 77-78)
  - Pledges: March-May 1948 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Pledges: June 1948 (Box 9, Folder 80-81)
  - Pledges: July-October 1948 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Pledges: Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Policy Committee (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Policy Committee Minutes, 1949-1950, 1952, 1956-1958 (Box 38, Folder 364)
  - Postage Stamp Report 1953 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Property Committee 1949 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Reassignment and Rearrangement of Office Space, 1948-1949 (Box 38, Folder 365)
  - Report on Mental Hygiene, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 366)
  - Search for Field Program Director 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Staff Meetings 1951-1954 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Staff Minutes, 1957 (Box 38, Folder 367)
  - Student Fellowship Committee Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 38, Folder 368)
  - Student Questions on World Mission (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Survey re. Non-Caucasian Candidates for Missions, 1945-1946 (Box 38, Folder 369)
  - SVM's Relationship to NCCCUSA, USCC, and Its Changing Mission, 1938-1953 (Box 38, Folder 370)
  - SVM Staff Job Descriptions and Minutes, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 371)
  - Testimonials, 1950 (Box 38, Folder 372)
  - Travel Staff (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Treasury Department (Box 10, Folder 91)
- Field Work Addendum, Series VI
  - Advances for Traveling Secretaries, 1949-1950 (Box 39, Folder 373)
  - Annual Field Report, 1950-1954 (Box 39, Folder 374)
  - Annual Field Report, 1955-1956 (Box 39, Folder 375)
  - Annual Field Report, 1956-1957 (Box 39, Folder 376)
  - Annual Field Report, 1957-1959 (Box 39, Folder 377)
  - Annual SVM Missionary Retreat in New England, April 16-18, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 378)
  - Briefing Conference for Traveling Staff, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 379)
  - Briefing Conference for Traveling Staff, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 380)
  - Briefing Conference for Traveling Staff, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 381)
  - Briefing Conference for Traveling Staff, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 382)
  - Briefing Conference for Traveling Staff, 1957 (Box 39, Folder 383)
  - Briefing Conference for Traveling Staff, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 384)
  - Briefing Conference for Traveling Staff, 1959 (Box 39, Folder 385)
  - Campus Coverage Report, 1947-1949 (Box 39, Folder 386)
  - Campus Visits, 1957 (Box 39, Folder 387)
  - Conference of Candidate Secretaries, November 1, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 388)
  - Conference on Student Travel, December 3-4, 1953 (Box 39, Folder 389)
  - Correspondence, Bonham, Dr. Kenneth W. re. Traveling Work, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 390)
  - Correspondence, Conrow, Marion (Traveling Secretary), 1944-1945 (Box 40, Folder 391)
  - Correspondence, General, 1952-1953 (Box 40, Folder 392)
  - Correspondence, re. Military Traveling Secretary, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 393)
  - Correspondence, re. Wolrd Youth Congress, 1937-1938 (Box 40, Folder 374)
  - Draft Outline of a Pamphlet to the Local Campus on the World Mission and SVM, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 395)
  - Essays and Hints to Missionary Speakers, 194? (Box 40, Folder 396)
  - Excerpts from Report of a 1949 Traveling Secretary (Box 40, Folder 397)
  - Field Program Committee, Meeting Agenda, Documents, and Minutes, November 21, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 398)
  - Field Program/ Field Service/ Field Work (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Field Program Director Search 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Field Program Committee, Meeting Agendas, Documents, and Minutes, May 8, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 399)
  - Field Program Committee, Meeting Agenda, and Minutes, November 20, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 400)
  - Field Program Committee, Meeting Agendas and Documents, October 8, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 401)
  - Field Program Committee, Meeting Agenda and Draft Minutes, January 20, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 402)
  - Field Program Committee, Meeting Agenda and Documents, September 20, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 403)
  - Field Program Committee, Meeting Agenda and Documents, December 17, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 404)
  - Field Program Committee, Meeting Agenda and Documents, September 19, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 405)
  - Field Program Committee, Minutes, 1952, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 406)
  - Miscellaneous Memos and Reports, 1952-1953 (Box 40, Folder 407)
  - Notes about Literature sent to Traveling Secretaries, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 408)
  - Notes sent to Traveling Secretaries, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 409)
  - Plan for SVM Work in New England, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 410)
  - Preliminary Listing of SCM Conference, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 411)
  - Publicity Sheets for Traveling Secretaries, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 412)
  - Schedule of College Visits, 1953-1954 (Box 40, Folder 413)
  - Silver Bay Conferences, 1941-1942, 1946 (Box 40, Folder 414)
  - Speaker's Kit: Overseas Relief, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 415)
  - Training Projects (Foreign Missions), 1943 (Box 41, Folder 416)
  - Travel Expenses of Former Secretaries, 1944-1945 (Box 41, Folder 417)
  - Travel Expense Statements of Traveling Secretaries, A-B, 1945-1949 (Box 41, Folder 418)
  - Travel Expense Statements for Traveling Secretaries, C-G, 1945-1949 (Box 41, Folder 419)
  - Travel Expense Statements for Traveling Secretaries, H-L, 1945-1949 (Box 41, Folder 420)
  - Travel Expense Statements for Traveling Secretaries, M-R, 1945-1950 (Box 41, Folder 421)
  - Travel Expense Statements for Traveling Secretaries, S, 1945-1950 (Box 41, Folder 422)
  - Travel Expense Statements for Traveling Secretaries, T, 1945-1949 (Box 42, Folder 422)
  - Travel Expense Statements for Traveling Secretaries, T-W, 1945-1950 (Box 42, Folder 423)
  - Traveling Secretary Reports, 1953 (Box 42, Folder 424)
- Publications and Literature Distribution Addendum, Series VII
  - Committee Records
    - Balance Sheets, 1943 (Box 42, Folder 425)
    - Comments on Richard Shaull's Encounter With Revolution, 1954-1955 (Box 42, Folder 426)
    - Correspondence, AB Publication Society, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 427)
    - Correspondence, Department of Commerce -- Bureau of Census, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 428)
    - Correspondence re. Encounter With Revolution, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 429)
    - Correspondence, Francis V. Toppin Company, 1952-1954 (Box 42, Folder 430)
    - Correspondence, Intercollegian, 1940-1949 (Box 42, Folder 431)
    - Correspondence re. Requests for Plays, 1941-1947 (Box 42, Folder 432)
    - Correspondence re. Requests for SVM Publications, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 433)
    - Correspondence re. Shaull's Manuscript to Publishers, 1954 (Box 42, Folder 434)
    - Correspondence, Sowers Printing Company, 1940-1944 (Box 42, Folder 435)
    - Draft for brochure, 1946-1947 (Box 42, Folder 436)
    - Draft of SVM Newsletter and Coordination of Mailouts, 1954 (Box 42, Folder 437)
    - Expenses, 1939-1942 (Box 42, Folder 438)
    - Information for SVM Newsletter, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 439)
    - Inventory List, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 440)
    - Inventory of Publications, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 441)
    - Literature Committee Minutes, 1955-1958 (Box 43, Folder 442)
    - Literature Committee Minutes, Notes, etc, 1956-1958 (Box 43, Folder 443)
    - Literature Committee Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 43, Folder 444)
    - Literature Copyrights, 1916-1937 (Box 43, Folder 445)
    - Manuscript of Christian Youth and Race Question by Olivia P. Stokes and Winburn Thomas includes critiques, 1944-1947 (Box 43, Folder 446)
    - Manuscript of Communism and the Revolution of Our Time, September 1954 (Box 43, Folder 447)